# LATHIF SHARIEFF

AI ASIC enthusiast seeking dynamic opportunities to excel and innovate

 $\P$  Germany J +49-15758185645  $\blacksquare$  sharieff.lathif@gmail.com  $\blacksquare$  linkedin.com/lathifs  $\clubsuit$  lathifs.tech

# Summary

Motivated and accomplished graduate student specializing in Hardware-Software co-design of AI ASIC architecture, equipped with practical experience gained from diverse internships and projects. With a strong foundation in AI hardware and in-depth knowledge of Domain-Specific Accelerator principles.

## Experience

Gemesys June 2023 – Present

AI Engineer - Working Student

Germany

- Developing and deploying customized AI solutions on a proprietary in-house AI ASIC and pioneering the exploration of cutting-edge Tensorflow-based AI models and algorithms exclusively crafted for low-power and edge devices.
- Spearheading cross-functional collaboration with software and hardware engineers to implement and optimize AI models
  on an in-house AI ASIC for training.

# University of Tübingen

May 2023 - Present

Master Thesis - DSP Engine for ML Accelerator

Stuttgart, Germany

• Architecting and implementing a high-performance DSP engine with MFCC extraction for a custom ML accelerator, specifically designed for efficient audio processing in ML applications and developing a robust streaming interface utilizing the ARM-AMBA protocol, facilitating seamless integration of the accelerator templates into the **UltraTrail**.

### Bosch Centre for Artificial Intelligence

Oct 2022 - Mar 2023

Deep Learning Hardware Engineer Intern

Stuttgart, Germany

- Assisted in developing and implementing the RTL design for an in-house AI IP (Neural Computing Engine), driving significant performance enhancement of AI IP.
- Mapped neural networks on silicon (FPGA) and implemented state-of-the-art on-chip interconnection bus interfaces.
- Expertly executed RTL simulation of the previously developed AI IP, CESARIA, utilizing advanced EDA and tool-chain software within Linux and Git-based environments.
- Contributed to the micro-architecture design of AI IP while conducting extensive research and analysis

### **Projects**

Audio Processing using FPGA | Verilog, Lattice ice40, iCEcube, I2S, I2C, SPI

• Developed and executed an innovative Master's project in collaboration with Telocate GmbH, designing an Audio processing system using a Lattice FPGA, Audio Codec, and MEMS microphone.

HoloCube puzzle using esp32 | C, Arduino IDE, NFC, MQTT, Altium, FreeCAD

• Led a multinational team in the development of a puzzle for Ubiquitous Lab. Conceptualized a challenging ESP32-based puzzle. It was implemented using an IMU and NFC card with a human-machine interface (HMI).

Design and analysis of 10 port router for NoC | Verilog, NoC, Xilinx Spartan-6, ISE design

• Spearheaded a team to design and implement a router for NoC on a FPGA. The project was awarded by IISc, India.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: SystemVerilog, Verilog, Python (TensorFlow & PyTorch), C, TCL

Developer Tools and IDEs: Cadence Xcelium, Xilinx Vivado & Vitis, ModelSim, Lattice iCEcube, Azure, Git

Technologies: RTL design (ASIC & FPGA flow), AI Accelerators, Neuromorphic computing

#### Education

## University of Freiburg

Apr 2021 - Present

 $Master\ of\ Science\ in\ Embedded\ Systems\ Engineering$ 

Freiburg, Germany

# Visvesvaraya Technological University

Aug 2016 - July 2020

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Telecommunication

Bangalore, India

#### Achievements

- Certifications: 1. Accelerators for Deep Learning IIT Roorke
- 2. Xcelium & Verilog Cadence
- 3. Innovation Management IBMI, Berlin
- 4. AI Product Management
- Awards: STIBET-I by DAAD, VELA Stipendiat by Eccelisia group and Maria-Ladenburger-Stipendium.
- Volunteering: Provided counseling and support to incoming master's students as an intercultural mentor.